Let's talk about how to build better
tools for your agents because the
effectiveness of your agents is really
dependent on the tools that are
available along with the intelligence of
the model. So I'm going to break it down
and we're going to look at some
practical insights and by the end
hopefully it will make you rethink how
you think about tool implementation. Now
the idea for this video came from this
blog post from Enthropic writing
effective tools for agents with agents.
So we're going to look at key findings
and some practical insights. But before
that we need to actually think about how
software engineering is changing with
agentic systems. So in traditional
software engineering you implement the
core functionality of a tool by wrapping
it around in a function. Now these are
deterministic systems. So you provide an
input you expect a deterministic
response. With tools it's actually
changing. Normally the input is a
natural language query. Then the agent
based on its own plan is going to decide
the steps it's going to take. It can
either make a tool call, use its
internal knowledge or even ask you a
follow-up question. And every time you
ask the same question, you are going to
see different steps the agent comes up
with. And normally these agentic systems
are part of the traditional software
engineering stack. So you really need to
rethink how you implement these systems.
So the blog post itself talks about
fourstep process on building good tools.
Our focus is going to be mainly on what
are the key principles around writing
better tools. But for the sake of
completeness, you want to first start
with an initial prototype that is going
to implement the core functionality.
Then you want to run evolves on the
tools that you implement. Then you want
to collaborate with a coding agent. So
basically using the intelligence of the
coding agents to help you improve your
tool description and tool implementation
and at the end of the day you want to
run evolves on it because if you can't
measure it you can't improve it and this
is normally an iterative process but
when it comes to implementation of the
tool themselves here are the key
principles I'll recommend to keep in
mind. The first one is choose the right
tools to implement. And don't worry,
we're going to talk about details of all
of these. Then make sure that you are
able to group different tools together.
This will help the agent select better
tools. Then we're going to talk a lot
about context engineering. So you want
to make sure that the input to the tool
is meaningful. Also, the return from the
tools are some meaningful context that
we can feed into the LLM. That will also
brings us the token efficiency because
we don't want to just fill up the
context of the model with useless
information. Prompt engineering is not
dead. So we're going to talk about how
to effectively prompt engineering tools
descriptions that are going to be
helpful for the LLM to select the
appropriate tool. And then more tools
don't always leads to better outcomes.
As with traditional software
engineering, small refinements yield
dramatic improvements.
Next, we're going to talk about each one
of these with more concrete and detailed
information. But I want you to look at
this flow. So let's say you have a task
that is provided to the agent. The agent
can select a number of different tools
for each of the subtasks. Now the input
and output of the tool is going to add
to the context window of the model or
the LLM or the agent and we'll need to
carefully think about how to preserve
only useful information in this context
window. A really good example of good
tools for AI agents is browser base.
They enable web browsing capabilities
for your AI agents and applications. So,
think of them as a cloud platform that
lets you host tools like Puppeteer and
Playright that can interact with your AI
agents and they are also the kind
sponsors of today's video. It's
extremely scalable, fast, and secure
platform that lets you create your own
custom agents for browser automation.
They have pre-existing browsing tools.
It enables workflow automation and can
also let you web scrape data from
websites. But the feature I like the
most is called stage hand. This is their
opensource AI browser automation
framework. So this enables browser
automation by defining actions and then
uh assigning tasks to the agents and
this comes with a very powerful SDK that
you can start using in your own
applications. This SDK has a number of
different existing agents including a
computer use agent and is fully
compatible with playright. So browser
automation is extremely easy with stage
hands. This lets you interact with
playright uh through natural language.
So for example, if you were to go to a
web page, this is the command that
you're going to use. Or if you want it
to uh take an action, you can just
describe that in natural language. Also,
it enables computer use agent. And the
best part is that if you want to scrape
data from any website, you can define
your own custom schema. The agent is
going to go extract that data and return
it to you. This is an extremely useful
tool for agents that are going to be
interacting with your web browser. Do
check them out. link is going to be in
the video description. Now back to the
video. So the first principle is
choosing the right tool for the task.
Now more tools does not mean going to
get better outcome. Actually they say
that they have seen a common error that
people just wrap existing software
functional or APIs in a tool and present
that as a tool to the agent. That's not
how you want to think about implementing
your tools. You want to think about the
context window of your LLM. So a tool
can have a cascade of multiple different
operations and you want to just generate
meaningful outcomes that the agent can
use. Okay, so here's a very simple
example of address book search. In
traditional software engineering, you
could implement a system that is going
to load all contacts in the memory. Then
iterate through each contact and if
there is a match that results is going
to be returned to you. Now you can write
multiple different tools for this if you
want to use this with an agentic system.
So for example there's one tool which is
going to be list contexts. It's return
you all 500 context. Then if you think
about it is let's say each contact is 50
tokens you're looking at about 25 uh,000
tokens then you can have either the
agent go through each one of them token
by token or you might have another tool
which go through it token by token right
at the end of the day you going to fill
up the context window of the agent with
useless information. Now instead of this
a good approach would be a tool that
searches using the traditional software
engineering setup and only return a very
small subset of contacts that it thinks
are meaningful. It could be just a
simple rack system and then you pass on
that result to the agent because the
agent is just looking for that one or
two context. So the way you think about
it is that when you're designing tools,
you should think about how humans
interact with those tools. So for
example, you want to have search
mechanism, not browse, filter, don't
scan, and navigate, don't iterate on
things. So here are some more examples.
Instead of implementing list users, list
event, create events like three
different separate tools, consider
implementing schedule event, which finds
availability and schedule an event. And
essentially you are wrapping multiple
different steps inside a single tool.
Another example is instead of
implementing read logs tool consider
implementing search tool which only
returns relevant logs and some
surrounding text. Again search don't
scan. Another idea is name spacing your
tools. So you want to group similar
tools together. Now, right now we have a
dozen of MCPs that an agent can have
access to and each one of them might be
implementing very similar functionality.
Now, if the agent has to decide which
tool to pick, there is a high
probability it will get confused. So,
it's here's a very simple
representation. Let's say there are a
number of different MCP servers. Each
one of them is implementing search,
create, update, delete, so on and so
forth. Right? Now without grouping them
together based on the MCP server if
they're using similar names the agent is
going to get confused. However, if you
group them together so for example
there's a name space for Slack messages
then there are tools specific to Jira
you add these prefixes to each of the
tool then it's going to really help the
agent determine which tool to use for
which task. They have a very interesting
insight. So there seems to be a
difference if you use a prefix or suffix
when it comes to the tool use evaluation
of the agent, right? So you probably
want to experiment with both. So put the
name space before or after the tool name
and see whether it's going to have any
impact on the tool usage or tool call
performance. So even though these
systems are getting smarter and smarter,
they can be tripped by these very small
nuance changes. Okay. So the next
pattern is how do you think about
returning information from a tool? So
whenever you have a tool call you're
going to get results. So what exactly do
you add in those results? Now the common
logic is going to be add as much
information as possible but that can
actually backfire. So they say tool
implementation should take care of to
return only high signal information back
to the agent and you want to make sure
that that information actually makes
sense. So instead of returning low-level
technical identifiers like UU ID or
maybe some encrypted image URL, you want
to return fields like name, image URL
which are more descriptive. Now in some
there are cases in which those low-level
technical identifiers can also be
helpful. So you want to return
structured outputs or structured formats
in which you preserve both low-level and
highle details. According to them,
agents tends to grapple with natural
language names, terms, and identifiers
significantly more successfully than
they do with cryptic identifiers. Now
another question, shall should you
return it in XML format, JSON, markdown?
Right now, that really depends on how
your models were trained. Claude, for
example, loves XML format and OpenAI
models also tend to like XML now. They
used to be pretty good at JSON, right?
So, you actually want to look at the
model that you're using and based on
that you decide what is going to be your
return data format. Next, you want to
think about optimizing tool response in
terms of the number of tokens that
you're returning. Again context
management is going to be critical. So
optimizing the quality of context is
important but so is optimizing the
quantity of context return back to the
tool as a response. Now they suggest for
longer context that is going to be
returned use pagenation range selection
or some sort of filtering or creation
mechanisms. By default code restricts
tool responses to 25,000 tokens. Now
keep in mind if you're going to be
making let's say 12 tool calls in order
to perform an operation this is going to
add up. So you want to be really careful
of about how much information you
actually want to return. One way is to
simply create responses for this. There
are a few strategies. For example, you
can directly encourage agents to pursue
more token efficient strategies like
making small and targeted searches
instead of a single broad search for
knowledge retrieval tasks. Very similar
to the context book example that we
talked about. Now, last but not the
least, prompt engineering for tool
description. This is a piece that I
often find people ignore, but I think it
needs a lot more attention. So the way
to think about this is if the agent is
going to select a tool, it's going to
mainly look at what the description of
the tool is and what are the input
outputs. You want to pay close attention
to what the tool is supposed to do. Also
properly name the input variables and
the outputs from the tool along with the
specs of the functionality. Now a very
easy way of thinking about this is that
if you hire a new intern what type of
information they will need assuming that
they don't know anything about your
system or your setup right so with that
in mind you want to also provide
specialized query formats definition of
niche terminologies relationship between
underlyings resources and make it
explicit. The idea is avoid any sort of
ambiguity where the agent will have to
make any assumptions. This is critical.
Communication is the main key between a
really good agentic system and a failed
agentic system which is confused on tool
selection. The rest of the article
mainly focuses on how to improve these
tools with agents. The idea is very
simple. You come up with the initial
implementation of your tool. Then you
need to come up with realw world
evolution test cases. Now this is
critical because a lot of times what I
have seen is that people will come up
with synthetic examples which have
nothing to do with the actual real world
use case. And it's very sad because
these systems do really well on those
synthetic evolves but when it comes to
real world tests they fail. And the
reason is that when you're building
these test sets or evol sets, you are
not actually capturing the real world
use cases. So if you follow all the
recommendations,
then if you want to iterate on those
tools with the agent, you want to
provide as much information as possible.
So that will include all the
documentation that is going to be
necessary. And the idea would be you
come up with an evol set where you can
test the agent. Also, you want to make
sure that you want to test it in complex
scenarios where you combine multiple
different tools instead of testing tools
in isolations. So, for example, here's a
weak task for test. So, if you ask a
tool or an agent, schedule a meeting
with a person next week, right? The
agent might just select that one tool
and schedule the meeting. However, your
test should look something like this.
schedule a meeting with Jane next week
to discuss our latest, let's say, a
project. Attach the notes from our
latest project planning meeting and
reserve a conference room. Right now,
this will involve the agent to plan and
then select multiple different tools in
order to accomplish that plan. This is
probably a more realistic real world
test case rather than having a very
simple single tool selection example in
your evaluation data set. And again this
is critical. I have seen a lot of
failures where people run simple evolve
test while they're building their
systems and those systems fail because
of the complexity in real world. After
that you can have an agentic loop. So
basically with the given set of ewalls
you run this in a loop. You gather the
information also you're going to look at
the feedback that the system generates
and then you use that feedback along
with the agents to improve upon your
tools. Now based on their internal test
they show that if you use the agent to
improve your tool you can actually get
substantially better performance. Now do
let me know if you want me to create
more detailed videos on the evaluation
setup. There are a couple of notebooks.
I'm going to put them in the video
description. But I hope you found this
video useful and if you need help with
building better systems, you can reach
out to me. Details are going to be in
the video description. Anyways, I hope
you found this video useful. Thanks for
watching and as always, see you in the
next one.